Guide to the James Hosmer Penniman Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
James Hosmer Penniman collection
1653-1944
MS 9
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(8 boxes)
Contains correspondence of James Hosmer Penniman, teacher, educator, and literary and historical collector. The rest of the papers consist of Penniman's collection of historical documents, correspondence, diaries, manuscripts, other papers and books on the subject of education. Included here is a discrete collection of David Francis Lincoln (1841-1916) papers containing correspondence and research notes on Lincoln's studies on various aspects of education.
Penniman, James Hosmer, 1860-1931
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James H. Penniman, 1921-1926, and of the Penniman family, 1931.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence. II. Subject Files. III. Legal Papers. IV. Educational Materials. V. David Francis Lincoln. VI. Engravings.
Scope and Contents
The James Hosmer Penniman Collection consists of three separately acquired groups: personal papers of Penniman; manuscripts relating to education and American history collected by Mr. Penniman and given to the Yale University Library from 1921 through 1926; and materials acquired from various sources relating to education which were added to the collection after his death as part of the Penniman Memorial Library of Education.
James Hosmer Penniman (1860-1931) graduated from Yale in 1884. Yale relatives whose papers are also at Yale include James Lanman (B.A. 1788), Matthew and Roger Griswold (both B.A. 1780), and Charles J. Lanman (B.A. 1814). After 28 years as a teacher and administrator of the Lower School of the DeLancey School, Philadelphia, Mr. Penniman retired in 1913 and devoted the remainder of his life to literary pursuits and travel. He founded the Maria Hosmer Penniman Memorial Library of Education at the University of Pennsylvania (1915), the Penniman Memorial Library of Education at Brown (1921) and the Penniman Memorial Library of Education at Yale (1920). To the volumes on education already in the university library, Dr. Penniman added books, magazines, and reports, and rare books and manuscripts as the opportunity offered. He gave to the Library more than 4000 books and 1000 pamphlets, and from funds provided by him more than 6200 volumes were purchased up to the time of his death. To maintain and increase the library, he endowed a fund of $50,000 in 1927.
In addition to his interest in libraries and education, Mr. Penniman was an internationally known authority on George Washington and the early history of the United States and a collector of Washingtoniana. Some of the manuscripts in the collection relate to the preparation of many of his books which included: Common Words Difficult To Spell (1891), Practical Suggestions In School Government (1899), Books And How To Make The Most Of Them (1910), George Washington As Commander In Chief (1917), George Washington As Man Of Letters (1918), George Washington At Mount Vernon (1921), Our Debt To France (1921), What Lafayette Did For America (1921), Philadelphia In The Early Eighteen Hundreds (1923).
At the time of his death, he had largely completed a two-volume work on George Washington. Some of the letters relate to his proposal to build the "Highway of the Thirteen Original States," from Washington to Mount Vernon.
In August, 1982, an autograph book, kept ca. 1875-1882 by James H. Penniman, was added to the collection. Because of the value of some of the autographs (e.g., Presidents Grant and Hayes), this item has been placed in the Security File.
Biographical / Historical
Teacher and administrator of the Lower School of the DeLancey School, Philadelphia (1885-1913); founded Maria Hosmer Penniman Memorial Library of Education at the University of Pennsylvania (1915), Penniman Memorial Library of Education at Brown (1921), Penniman Memorial Library of Education at Yale (1920); author on George Washington and the early United States, and collector of Washingtoniana.
Arithmetic -- Textbooks -- To 1846; Education -- Connecticut; Education -- Massachusetts; Education -- United States -- History; Education; Penmanship; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; Account books; Engravings (prints); Textbooks; Educators; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Drinker, Henry S. (Henry Sturgis), 1850-1937; Gillette, William, 1853-1937; Graves, Frank Pierrepont, 1869-1956; Lincoln, David F. (David Francis), 1841-1916; Mack, Connie, 1862-1956; Metternich, Clemens Wenzel Lothar, Fürst von, 1773-1859; Penniman, James Hosmer, 1860-1931; Penniman, James Lanham, 1832-1890; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Plimpton, George A. (George Arthur), 1855-1936; Rogers, James Gamble, 1867-1947; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Wanamaker, Rodman, 1863-1928; Zimbalist, Mary Louise Curtis Bok, 1876-1970; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1884
- Correspondence, 1718-1944; Series I; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence is divided into two sections. The first section includes letters, postcards, and telegrams as well as newspaper clippings, miniature water colors and envelopes received by J.H. Penniman. These relate to his personal and professional activities which include the founding of a number of memorial libraries, the proposal of his highway plan, various publishing endeavors and his involvement in education. Correspondence in this section is arranged alphabetically by author and then chronologically for each author. Individual correspondents include Theodore Roosevelt, James Rowland Angell and John Grier Hibben.
  The second section is comprised of collected correspondence, newspaper clippings and autographs of other individuals including many eminent American and European historical figures, men associated with educational institutions and graduates of Yale University. Biographical information has been added to a considerable portion of the material. This section of correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author and then by addressee for each author. Individual correspondents include Aba-el-Kadu, Cardinal Alteri, the Duke of Argyll, Aaron Burr, John C. Calhoun, Henry Clay, Paul Du Chaillu, William E. Gladstone, Sir William Hamilton, Kalakana Rex, Lord Lyttledon, Alfred Thayer Mahan, Rembrandt Peale, Jonathan Trumbull, Daniel Webster.
  - Correspondence received by J.H. Penniman
    - Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949, 1926 December 30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Benjamin, W.R., 1924 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bok, Mary Louise, 1924 December 16, 1926 February 2, 1927 November 15, 1929 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Elmer E., 1926 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bullard, R.L., n.y. March 20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cadman, S. Parkes, 1930 January 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Carson, Hampton L., 1922 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Castle, Neville H., 1928 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Coley, Edw. Huntington, 1928 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Comegys, Harriet Clayton, 1926 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Daugherty, Mrs. P., n.y. November 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959, 1928 December undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dior, Lucien (note), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Drinker, Henry S., 1921 November 24, November 26 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fitzpatrick, John C., 1927 April 5, 1929 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Garland, Thomas J., 1927 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - French, Daniel C., 1921 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Gillette, William, 1853-1937, 1923 January 15, 1923 June 14, 1924 October 16, 1924 November 11, 1926 September 4, 1927 April 21, 1928 January 15, 1928 December 12, 1929 January 15, 1929 June 28, 1929 October 24, 1929 October 26, 1929 October undated, 1929 December 25 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Grammen, Carl E., 1923 March 9, 1924 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Graves, Frank Pierrepont, 1924 November 11, 1925 November 5, 1929 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Grizzelle, G.D., 1929 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Hibben, John Grier, 1927 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Hiley, F.C.W., 1929 April 30, 1929 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Keen, W.W., 1929 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Keogh, Andrew, 1929 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Kinley, David, 1927 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Koopman, H.L., 1925 September 22, 1929 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Lowell, Anna (Mrs. A. Lawrence) with note by Penniman, 1933 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Lyman, R.M., 1925 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Mack, Connie (i.e., Cornelius McGillicuddy), 1926 July 22, 1929 September 28, 1928 March 26, 1928 July 30, 1929 March 6, 1929 August 31 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Martin, Edward, 1927 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Miller, Park Hays, 1928 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Newton, A. Edward, 1924 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Northrop, Cyrus, 1918 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Paltsits, Victor H., 1927 February 21, 1929 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1921 January 18, 1926 March 17, 1928 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Pier Arthur S., 1926 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Plimpton, George A., 1929 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Repplier, Agnes (Mrs. Charles S.), 1929 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Rogers, James Gamble, 1926 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1918 May 28, 1918 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Smith, Edgar F., 1922 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Spaulding, F.E., 1928 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Stires, Ernest M., 1930 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1923 May 6, 1929 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Swann, Arthur, 1925 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Taft, William Howard, 1920 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 46a)
    - Thomas, Augustus, 1922 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Tompkins, Abigail Brown, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      General
      miniature watercolors
    - Wanamaker, Rodman, 1908 March 5, 1917 December 27, 1923 December 1, 1926 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Whorton, Anne H., 1923 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Williams, William, 1928 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Wilson, Frances, 1930 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Windoor, E., 1918 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Wolcott, J.D., 1911 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Wurtz, John S., 1930 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence of Others
    - Abd-el-Kader to General Baron Durieu, with French translation, 1862 July (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Abbott, John Stevens Cabot (1805-1877) to Coates, Henry, 1860 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Erben, P. Jr., 1860 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Alcott, William Andrus (1798-1859) to Unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Allsors, E. to Fairchild, Milton, n.y. October 28 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Altieri (Cardinal) to Ponzi, Giuseppe (Prof.) with English translation, 1859 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Anglus, Charles E. to Joline, Adrian H., 1908 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Argyll, George Douglas Campbell, 8th duke of, Letter on education, teaching Gaelic, 1876 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Babbage, Charles (1792-1871) to Mrs. Strutt, 1850 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Bacon, Ezekiel (1776-1870) Hubbard, Edward, 1842 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey (1830-1907) to The Independent, 1860 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter (1809-1889) to Short, Prof. Charles (1821-1886), 1868 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Barrington, William Augustus Curzon (1842- ?) Carlisle, James Mandeville (1814-1877), 1867 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Bell, Alexander Melville (1819-1905) to Green, James C., 1889 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Bigelow, John (1817-1911) to Weidemeyer, John William (1819-, 1887 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Bradley, Emily T. to Green, J.C., 1892 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Bright, John (1811-1889) Note admitting bearer to… (autograph), 1877 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Buehler, H.G. to Fairchild, Milton, 1910 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Burr, Aaron to
    - Calhoun, John C. to
      - Cist, Lewis Jacob (1818-1885), 1842 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 76)
      - Yale College, 1844 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 76)
      - Yates, Joseph Christopher, 1824 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 76)
      - Autograph (Filed with ALS W.P. Starke to J.C. Green, 1886 Jun 10), undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Carey, Henry Charles (1793-1879) to Griswold, Rufus Wilmot (1815-1857), 1851 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Chalmers, Thomas (1780-1847) Certificate of attendance of Mr. Finley Macpherson, New College, Edinburgh., 1847 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Chambers, William (1800-1883) to Woliki, Mr., 1847 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Chauvenet, William (1820-1870) to Hilgard, Julius Erasmus (1825-1891), 1869 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Claretie, Jules Absène Arnand to Unidentifed, 1902 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Clark, Peter/Testimony recommending Ames Angier as teacher at North School, Boston., 1719 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Clay, Henry to
      - Bacon, David Francis (1813-1865), 1843 October 27, 1845 January 6, 1845 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - Bishop, William Darius (1827-1904), 1848 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - Collier, Col. James (1789-1873), 1828 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - Oakes, 1833 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - Madison, James (1751-1836), 1828 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - Young Men's Clay Association of N.Y.C., 1846 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Combo, George (1788-1858) to
      - Capen, Nahum (1804-1886), with newspaper clipping, 1836 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Jameson, Anna Brownell (1794-1860), 1845 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Comstock, John Lee (1789-1858) to Hall, Prof. Frederick (1780-1843), 1822 August 30 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Conkling, Roscoe (1829-1888) to Henry, Mrs. Pauline E., 1870 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Cook, Joseph (1838-1901) to Unidentified, 1893 August 26 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Cooper, Peter (1791-1883) to
      - Vanheynegen, William B., 1875 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 88)
      - Biographical newspaper clipping, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Daggett, David (1764-1851) to (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Dana, James D. to
      - Ansted, David Thomas (1814-1880), 1847 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - Gray, Asa (1810-1888) (See Register, Nat. Sci. Mss Group), 1864 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - Hilgard, Julius Erasmus (1825-1891), 1879 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - Autograph, 1857 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Day, Jeremiah to Fositt, Edward Campbell, 1829 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Denison, William to
      - Southwick, Albert, with report on Winthrop, 1860 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - Institute for Young Ladies, 1860 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Dix, Morgan (1827-1908) to Patterson, Mrs., n.y. June 11 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Dixon, William Hepworth (1821-1879) to Squier, Ephraim George (1821-1888), 1867 July 17 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Drummond, Henry (1851-1897) to Cuyler, Dr. Theodore Ledyard (1822-1909), 1887 July 31 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - DuChaillu, Paul Belloni (1835-1903) Autograph, 1872 April (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Ely, Richard Theodore (1854-1943) to Childs, George William (1829-1894), 1890 April 24 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Fisher, Irving, (1867-1947) to Fairchild, Milton, 1910 April 21 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Froude, J. Ames Anthony (1818-1894) to Badeau, Adam (1831-?), 1870 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - George, Henry (1839-1897) to Ed. North American Review, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Gildersleeve, Basil Lanneau (1831-1894) to Brome, W. Hard, 1873 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Gillette, William to
      - Keogh, Alexander, 1930 February 14 (Box 2, Folder 102)
      - Secretary of Yale College, 1937 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 102)
      - Facsimiles of congratulatory letters sent to William Gillette, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Gladstone, William Ewart (1809-1898) Autograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Gould, Benjamin Apthorp to
      - Green, James C., 1889 November 22 (Box 2, Folder 104)
      - Hayes, Isaac Israel, (1832-1881), 1860 July 3, 1860 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 104)
      - Hilgard, Julius Erasmus (1825-1891), 1876 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Hadley, Arthur Twining (1856-1930) to Fairchild, Milton, 1906 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Hamilton, William (Sir) (1788-1856) to Cozswell, [Joseph Green] (1786-1871), undated (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Hitchcock, Edward (1793-1863) to unidentified correspondent, 1852 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 106a)
    - Howitt, William (1792-1879) to Baldwin, Cradock and Joy, 1823 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Hutchins, William James (1871-?) to Keogh, Mrs. Andrew, 1933 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Jeffrey, Francis (1773-1850) to Malthus, Thomas Robert (1766-1834), 1820 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Kalakaua Rex, King of the Sandwich Is. (Hawaii) Autograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Kane, John Kintzing (1795-1858) to Bache, Alexander Dallas (1806-1867), 1844 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Knight, Charles (1791-1873) to Packer, Mr., undated (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Lait, C. to Trumbull, John, 1818 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Lancaster, Joseph (1778-1838) to
      - Bistill, John, 1807 [August or Sep] (Box 2, Folder 114)
      - Henry, Alexander (1766-1847), 1834 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 114)
      - Wise, Henry Alexander (1806-1876), 1838 May 9 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Landon, Melville de Lancey (1839-1910) to Morgan, M.H., 1881 August 22 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Leavenworth, Elias Warner (1803-1887) to Lanman, Charles (1819-1895), 1875 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Lehar, Franz (1870-?) to König, 1913 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Leighton, Baron Frederic of Stretton (1830-1896)
      - Autograph, Rome, 1885 October (Box 2, Folder 118)
      - Newspaper clipping, 1886 January 25 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Lieber, Francis (1800-1872) to Francis, [John Wakefield, 1789-1861], 1845 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Lodge, Edmund (1756-1839) to Nicol, W., 1823 August 15 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Lubbock, Sir John (1834-1913) to Phillips, H., Jr., 1892 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Lynde, William Pitt (1817-1885) to Lamar, Charles, with biographical information., 1875 July 1 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Lyttleton, George William, 4th Baron to Briggs, Rev. L.C., 1866 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Mackenzie, Morell (Sir) to
      - Green, James C., 1877 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 124)
      - Newspaper clipping, 1888 October 15, 1892 February 4, undated (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Mackintosh, Sir James (1765-1832) to
      - Brevoort, Henry (1791-1874), Circa 1827 November (Box 2, Folder 125)
      - Rich, Obadiah (1783-1850), Circa 1829 (Box 2, Folder 125)
      - Engraving, undated (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Mahan, Alfred Thayer (1840-1914) to Unidentified, 1900 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Mahon, Lord (Stanhope, Philip Henry, 5th Earl, 1805-1875) (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Autograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Mansfield, Jared (1759-1830) to Howe, Hezekiah (1775-1838), 1817 February 24 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Mills, Higley Mary to Myers, Mrs., n.y. September 15 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Milner, Alfred (Sir) to Coolbrith, Ina (Miss) (1854-?), 1914 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Mitchell, Samuel Latham (1764-1831) to Cleaveland, Parker (1780-1858), 1817 August 23 (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Moberly, George, Lord Bishop of Salisbury to Briggs, L.C., 1870 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Morris, Lewis to Morris, James, 1800 April 15, 1801 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Mott, Alexander Brown (1826-1889) to Rice, James C., 1863 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Müller, Friedrich Max (1827-1900) to
      - Donkin, Miss, 1856 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 135)
      - Newspaper clipping, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - Murat, Napoleon Lucien Charles (Prince) to Bayard, William, 1826 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - Murray, Joseph
      - Joinder in demurrer in case of Thomas Vartor vs. John Trumbull, undated (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Murray, William Henry Harrison to Daniels, Mr., 1891 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Nadaillac, Jean Francois A. du Pouget, Marquis de to Unidentified, 1884 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Nash, Treadway Russell (1725-1811) to Philips, Mr. (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Engraving of Worcester College and biographical information, [1783] April 26 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Olmsted, Denison (1791-1859) to Hall, Frederick (1780-1843), 1825 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Owen, Richard (1810-1890) to Rutter, (William) and Co., 1873 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Peabody, George (1795-1869) to Riggs, Peabody and Co., 1828 March 14 (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Peale, Rembrandt (1778-1860)
      - Autograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 144)
      - 2¢ U.S. stamp with his portrait of Washington on it, undated (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Peaslee, Edmund Randolph (1814-1878) to Cleaveland, Parker (1780-1858), 1844 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Poole, W.F. to Philis, Sir N., 1863 August 11 (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Porter, Noah (1811-1892) to Street, Augustus Russell (1791-1866), 1866 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Pownall, Thomas (1722-1805) to Sharp, W., undated (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - Reeves, John (1752?-1829) to Da Rocha, Dr., 1813 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - Rice James Clay (1829-1864) Endorsement with biographical information, 1863 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - Sankey, Ira David (1840-1908) to Steele, Mr., 1895 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Silliman, Benjamin (1779-1864)
      Transferred to Silliman Family Papers, there is no folder 52.
    - Smith, Goldwin (1823-1910) to
      - Bryce, Lloyd Stephens (1851-1917), 1895 February 26 (Box 2, Folder 153)
      - Field, Cyrus West (1819-1892), 1871 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 153)
      - Hinton, R.J., 1869 August 18 (Box 2, Folder 153)
      - Kingsbury, John (1801-1874), 1864 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 153)
      - Walford, [Edward], 1867 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 153)
      - Unidentified, 1890 May 6, 1896 April 17, undated [ca. 1869] (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Sothern, Edward Askew ("Lord Dundreary")/Autograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Stanley, Arthur Penrhyn to
      - Green, James C., 1892 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 155)
      - Ticket signed by him, 1865 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 155)
      - Unidentified, 1880 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Starke, William P. to
      - Green, James C. concerning J.C. Calhoun Calhoun autograph enclosed, 1886 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Storrs, Henry Randolph to
      - Applegate, John, 1825 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 157)
      - Bleeker and Sedgwick, 1817 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - Storrs, Richard Salter (1821-1900) to
      - Thompson, Joseph Parrish (1819-1879), 1878 December 17 (Box 2, Folder 158)
      - Unidentified, 1877 April 23 (Box 2, Folder 158)
      - Autographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - Sullivant, William Starling (1803-1873) to Austen, Mr., 1866 July 8 (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Swain, David Lowry (1801-1868) to Teft, J.K., 1867 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - Tinker, B.W. to Fairchild, Milton, 1910 September 28 (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Torrey, John to Willis, Oliver R., 1843 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - Trumbull, James Hammond (1821-1897) to
      - Dawson, Henry B., 1860 September 3 (Box 2, Folder 163)
      - Autograph note of Jonathan Trumbull, 1868 November 18, undated (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah to Cleaveland, Parker (1780-1858), 1818 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 164)